<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The case and justification of Sr. John Pettus, of the county of Suffolk, knight, concerning two charitable bills now depending in the House of Lords under his care. One for the better settling of Mr. Henry Smith's estate, according to the donor's true intention. The other for settling of charitable uses in the town of Kelshall, according to the desire of the chief land-owners and inhabitants there. Humbly represented to the Lords and Commons in Parliament. For the better regulating of them for the future.</title>
            <author>Pettus, John, Sir, 1613-1690.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B28072</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99885933</idno>
  <idno type="VID">188534</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248537223</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing P1904</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 816.m.16[31]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R225205</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99885933</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99885933e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B28072)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 188534)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C11:1[29])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The case and justification of Sr. John Pettus, of the county of Suffolk, knight, concerning two charitable bills now depending in the House of Lords under his care. One for the better settling of Mr. Henry Smith's estate, according to the donor's true intention. The other for settling of charitable uses in the town of Kelshall, according to the desire of the chief land-owners and inhabitants there. Humbly represented to the Lords and Commons in Parliament. For the better regulating of them for the future.</title>
                  <author>Pettus, John, Sir, 1613-1690.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[4] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Printed in the year 1677/8.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed at end: Jo. Pettus.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="corporate_name">Great Britain. --  Parliament --  History --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:188534:1"/>
            <p> THE Case and Justification OF S<seg rend="sup">r.</seg> JOHN PETTUS, Of the County of <hi>Suffolk,</hi> Knight, Concerning Two Charitable BILLS now Depending in the <hi>House of Lords</hi> under his Care.</p>
            <p>One for the better settling of Mr. <hi>Henry Smith</hi>'s Estate, according to the Donor's true Intention.</p>
            <p>The other for settling of <hi>Charitable Uses</hi> in the Town of <hi>Kelshall,</hi> according to the desire of the chief Land-Owners and Inhabitants there.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Humbly Represented to the Lords and Commons in PARLIAMENT.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>For the better Regulating of them for the future.</p>
            <p>Printed in the Year 1677/8.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:188534:2"/>
            <opener>
               <salute>MY LORDS,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>
               </hi> Joyn these two <hi>Bills</hi> together in one <hi>Case,</hi> because they are both now manag'd by ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tue of two <hi>Decrees</hi> obtain'd (as I conceive) by mis-representations; and both of them also manag'd (at present) by Persons not suitable or proper (as is conceiv'd) for the Trusts of them: So as these <hi>Acts</hi> are intended to make the Trusts more publick, and Obligations to the performers of the Charity intended by both.</p>
            <p>In relation to Your Lordships grandeur: I could not well reduce them into a lesser shape; and though they appear in a greater bulk then is usually presented, yet I assure Your Lordships they do not take above seven minutes to the reading of them; and I hope they will prove so satisfactory, that the concerning of my self in them, will be attributed rather to my Charitable dispo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sition, (for I intend a good to 224 Towns, in 32 Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties in <hi>England</hi> and <hi>Wales)</hi> then an injury to any man. My aim being, that so great a Charitable Gift may not be hid under a Bushel, but set in a publick place, (as it deserves) and also manag'd by publick Persons, so as the light and reputation of it, and my clear intents, may be seen by Your Lordships, and the Representatives of those Counties and Towns where they are.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:188534:3"/>
            <p> Protesting, that neither favour nor affection, or hopes of reward in this World, have in the least invited my endeavours for the settling these two <hi>Bills</hi> into <hi>Acts,</hi> for I have sufficiently contented my self, that I have given Your Lordships the opportunity of doing a great Good, by passing one, and giving the other a serene pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gress to the <hi>House of Commons:</hi> both being humbly submitted to Your Lordships wisdoms, by,</p>
            <closer>
               <salute>My Lords,</salute>
               <signed>Your Lordships most obedient and humble Servant, Jo. Pettus.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>